Angelo Ocana Martins

Address: Ottawa, ON E-mail: angeloocana@gmail.com

Phone: (613) 558-9571 Site: angeloocana.com

Github: github.com/angeloocana Pluralsight: pluralsight.com/profile/ocanaangelo

Objective

Senior Software Engineer looking for an opportunity to create performant experiences with JavaScript, Typescript, React, GraphQL, Apollo, and Nodejs on large applications that have a global impact, and be able to contribute with the opensource community.

About Me

Full Stack Developer for +14 years, architecting and building web applications. I'm curious and passionate to constantly learn new things and share with others.

I love collaborating with designers and engineers to create beautiful and fast applications using functional programing and test-driven development to write quality clean code, that can scale and be easy to maintain.

I would love to be able to work at a place where I can contribute back to the open source community.

My full stack development experience includes:

- Frontend: JavaScript, Typescript, React, React Native, Apollo, GraphQL, Redux, Webpack, RXjs, Angular, and JQuery.
- Backend: C# (MVC / Web forms), NodeJs, and PHP.
- Databases: SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, and Redis.
- Cloud: Azure, AWS, Heroku, and Netlify. (Experience with Kubernetes and docker).

Work Experience

2018 – Present Kinaxis

Principal Developer

- Design and architect mono repo for a large typescript and react web application.
- Improve performance and tracking memory leaks.
- Created own state management library inspired by redux, reselect and recoil.
- Mentor teammates, always providing help to the whole team.
- +100 pull requests reviewed monthly.
- Present regular internal Tech talks.
- Great collaboration with UX and PM to design and elaborate new features.

Technologies: React, Typescript, Redux, RxJS, Angular, C#, .net MVC, TDD, Jest/Jasmine, Webpack, styled-components, SASS, testcafe, ramda.

2007, 2015 - 2018

Senior Full-stack Developer | Latest Projects:

• budbuds.us

Coding | React Native, Redux, Graphql, Nodejs, Postgres, Redis, Kubernetes and Docker.

• tic-tac-toe-ai.surge.sh

Design and Coding | Html Canvas, React, Jest, Graphql, Nodejs, and Gatsby.

angeloocana.com

Design and Coding | React, Jest, Graphql, Nodejs, and Gatsby.

novoterritorio.azurewebsites.net

Coding | D3, Angular, Ionic, TypeScript, Jasmine, C#, MongoDB, Azure, SASS, and Gulp.

• staffgeist.com

Coding | Angular, Ionic, TypeScript, Jasmine, C#, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Azure, SASS, and Gulp.

• jumpoverjump.com

Design and Coding | Angular, Ionic, Jasmine, C#, MongoDB, Azure, SASS, and Gulp.

2011 – 2015 POL, Peela, Total On Demand

Lead Senior C# Software Developer

- Developed web platform for Small-Medium marketing and endomarketing campaigns,
 5-8 projects every year. 5K-9Million Users.
- Created their own e-commerce platform.
- Provided consultations to extract clients needs and develop strategies.

Technologies: Javascript, C#, .net MVC, Structuremap, Web Forms, JQuery, SQL Server, Postgres, DDD, TDD, Lucene, Elasticsearch, RabbitMQ, Heroku and Amazon AWS.

Clients: Loreal, Johnson, Sony, Vivo Telefonica, Volkswagen, Walmart, BASF, Net, FMC, FTD, Sky, OI, BRF, Syngenta, Cury, Tenda, B2W, Magazine Luiza, FastShop, ...et al.

2010 –2011 Empresário Cobrança

Lead C# Software Developer

- Developed web platform to manage debt collection.
- Worked with complex mathematical algorithms to calculate interest rates.
- Created company's own barcode generation software.
- Development of internal Human Resources systems.
- Building access control system using webcams.
- Developed an internal financial control system.
- Wrote performative queries to work with a 500GB SQL Server database over millions of rows.

Technologies: Javascript, C#, WCF, WPF, WebForms, Windows Forms, Windows Services, EXT.Net, Jquery, and SQL Server.

2010 –2010 Media W

C# Software Developer

Developed POS Desktop Terminal following government regulations.

2008 – 2010 Upgrade Consultoria

Junior C# Software Developer

- PriManager Developing web platform to manage large-scale construction environments.
- FDE Web platform for managing public schools in São Paulo/BR.
- Developed their own ERP & CRM.

Technologies: Javascript, C#, Webforms, Telerik, JQuery, Web Services, Windows Services, Flash, Action Script, and SQL Server.

Education

2012 – Present Pluralsight

Design and Technology

pluralsight.com/profile/ocanaangelo

2013 – 2014 UNIP - Universidade Paulista

Analysis and System Development

2011 - 2010 FIAP — Faculdade de Informática e Administração Paulista

Analysis and System Development

2007 - 2009 FIEB

Web Design with Emphasis on Digital Media

Languages

English	Portuguese	French	Spanish
Fluent	Native	Basic	Proficient